Finding Aid for the Elmer Belt Collection of Vinciana Graphic Arts LSC.2366
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Leonardo da Vinci, portrait within an oval., 19th century; lsc_2366_b004_005; Italian engraving. After Giuseppe Bossi (1777-1815).; 12.5 x 10.5 cm on 35 x 25 cm.
  Claudio Artaria inc. "All'Egregio Gautero della Belle Arte / II Sig.re Bartolomeo Turina / questa sua pro-izia / " Verlag Gebruder Rocca in Berlin und Goettingen. Gedruckt von Hampe. The portrait is almost identical with the one signed Bossi and Anderloni, but 0.5 cm wider.
- "Come gentle friend salute my bride...", undated; lsc_2366_b004_001; Leonardo, da Vinci, 1452-1519; Engraving.
  An engraving after Leonardo signed: "Leonardo Vinci (invit?) at bottom left of engraving. London (c1671-1707). Original and photoprint.
- Variant of 29, undated; lsc_2366_b004_006; Bossi, Giuseppe, 1777-1815; Anderloni, Faustino, 1766-1847
  Signed Bossi and Anderloni.
- Self portrait, 1766; lsc_2366_b004_007; Zocchi, Giuseppe, 1711-1767; Italian engraving. After Leonardo da Vinci.; 20.5 x 18 cm on 35 x 25 cm.
  "Lionardo di Ser Piero / da Vinci [coat of arms] pittore / Scultore, Architetto &c / nato nel MCCCCXLV. morto nel MDXX [sic] Dedicato al...Mse, el Cavre Alessandro Coppoli Patrizio Perugino, e Fiorentino. / Preso da un Quadro esistente nella Galleria di S.A.R. di Firenze. Below: Correct life data written in pencil.
- The Last Supper, circa 19th century; lsc_2366_b004_008; Roemhild; German engraving. After Leonardo da Vinci.; 19 x 28 cm (Margins cropped except for bottom) on 22 x 28 cm.
  Left: a Paris chez Dopler, rue St. Jacques No. 21. Right: Roemhild sc. Depose. Below within decorative scrolls: "La Cene-Das Abendmahl / En verite, je vous dis un de vous doit me livrer--In Wahreit ich sage Euch, Einer von Euch wird mich verrathen.
- Christ disputing with the doctors, 19th century; lsc_2366_b004_009; Radclyffe, William, 1780-1855; English engraving.; 13.5 x 17 cm on 21 x 27.5 cm.
  Below, centered: Engraved by W. Radclyffe. "Christ disputing with the doctors" / from the original Painting by Leonardo da Vinci in the National Gallery / No. 33 / Jones [and] Co of the Temple of the Muses, Finsbury Square, London.
- Leonardo da Vinci after a picture by himself engraved by Raffaello Morghen, circa 19th century; lsc_2366_b004_010; Posselwhite, J. (James), 1798-1884; English engraving.; 30.5 x 22 cm.
  London. Published by Charles Knight [and] Co. Ludgate St.
- Raphael's Burial, 17th-18th century; lsc_2366_b002_001; Le Sueur, Eustache, 1616-1655; French drawing. Red chalk over ink.; 24.2 x 38.5 cm.
  Inscription: "From coll. Le Sueur. Enterrement et mort de Raphael. Son corps est porte a la sepulture par les principaux eleves; son tableaux de la Transfiguration suit la marche est porte en triumph de lui.
- Caricatures after Leonardo da Vinci and Hieronymus Bosch, 17th century; lsc_2366_b002_002; Baccio del Bianco, Luigi, 1604-1656; Italian drawings. Pen and bistre.; 26.5 x 40 cm.
  Acquired in 1951 at Colnaghi in London as Ghezzi or Zenetti, but identified by B. Degenhart as Baccio del Banco.
  Supplements a set in the Staatliche Graphische Sammlung, Muenchen. This copy carries the number 139. The Munich set shows consecutive numbers.
- Vinci Landscape, circa 1957; lsc_2366_b002_003; Bret, Paul, 1902-; French drawing. Pencil.; 22 x 29 cm.
  Inscribed at bottom: "La tour de la Bibliotheque Vinci 57."
- Portrait of Leonardo da Vinci with a cap, 19th century; lsc_2366_b006_001; Leroux, Jean Marie, 1788-1870; Denoyer, B.; French engraving.; 30 x 24 cm. Impression: 38 x 30 cm on 40 x 32 cm.
  Cartouche in imitation of embroidery, carrying the inscription: Leonardo / de Vinci. Left: L. de Vinci pinx. Right: J.M. Leroux sc. Center: B. Denoyer del. Below: "Il naquit en 1452 au Chateau de Vinci pres de Florence/Peintre, Architecte et Sculpteur, Il fut invite par Francois 1er a se rendre en France/il y vint en 1515 et mourut a Ambroise au palais de Clou le 2 mai, 1519. Publie par Veith [and] Hauser, Paris." Below: depose a la direction. Left: Imprime par Chardin aine et Asc.
- Self-Portrait of Leonardo da Vinci, 18th-19th century; lsc_2366_b006_002; Morghen, Raffaello, 1761-1833; Italian engraving. After Leonardo da Vinci.; 24.5 x 29 cm. Impression: 30 x 22 cm on 41.5 cm x 32.8 cm.
  Water stains. Left: Leonardus Vincius se ipsum pincit. Right: Raphael Morghen sculpsit.
- Salome with head of John the Baptist., 19th century; lsc_2366_b006_003; Garavaglia, Giovita, 1790-1835; Italian engraving. After Bernardo Luini (1475-1533).; 25.5 x 30.3 cm.
  Below left: Bernardino Luini dip. Below right: Giovita Garavaglia inc. Center: Pietro Anderloni dec. "All Egregio Protettore delle Belle Arti/xxx il originale esiste presso il Cav. Prof. Scarpa." In Firenze presso Luigi Bardi.
- Hollar print P1578 - mat 1, undated; lsc_2366_b011_001
  Print by Wenceslaus Hollar (Prague, Bohemia 1607–1677 London, England.)
- Five Men, undated; lsc_2366_b011_002
- Two grotesque figures, undated; lsc_2366_b011_003
- Hollar print P1594i - folder 2, undated; lsc_2366_b011_004
- Hollar print P1595i - folder 2, undated; lsc_2366_b011_005
- Hollar print P1596i - folder 2, undated; lsc_2366_b011_006
- Hollar print P1605i - mat 3, undated; lsc_2366_b011_007
- Hollar print P1610i - mat 3, undated; lsc_2366_b011_008
- Hollar print P1723i - mat 3, undated; lsc_2366_b011_009
- Hollar print P1748i - mat 3, undated; lsc_2366_b011_010